We will study an embryonic tissue called the endoderm,
内胚葉と呼ばれる胚組織を研究します。
with a mesodermal tissue that is its packaging.
それは中胚葉組織、つまりその包装を伴います。
This means that I cannot study an endoderm without its envelope.
つまり、その包みなしには内胚葉を研究できないということです。
So we will study both the peritoneum and the digestive tract.
したがって、腹膜と消化管の両方を研究します。
We will see that what happens in the development of your brain,
脳の発達で何が起こるかを見ていきます。
there are synchronous phenomena here.
ここには同期現象があります。
So, it's important to see this unity, but also to understand that...
この一体性をよく見て、しかし理解してください...
this base of the skull is important.
この頭蓋底は重要です。
So, what will we start by studying?
では、まず何を研究しましょうか？
Essentially, we'll start by studying the face.
まず顔を研究します。
You remember, the embryo flexes.
覚えていますか、胚は屈曲します。
This will be a global reorganization of my embryo.
これは私の胚の全体的な再編成になります。
Initially, it's an open tissue.
最初は開いた組織です。
Through this flexion, it will delimit itself,
この屈曲によって、それは区画化され、
it will organize itself into specific spaces.
特定の空間に組織化されます。
And we will study these spaces one by one.
そして、これらの空間を一つずつ研究します。
Last time, we studied the neurocranium.
前回は神経頭蓋を研究しました。
This time, we will study the face.
今回は顔を研究します。
in detail from the peripheral part to the internal part up
末梢部分から内部部分まで、詳細に
to the mouth
口のレベルまで
with the globality of development and we will also integrate perhaps
発達全体を伴い、おそらく歯も少し統合します。
a little bit the teeth,
歯も少し統合します。
we will integrate the pituitary, we will integrate the thyroid, parathyroid up to the
下垂体、甲状腺、副甲状腺を胸腺レベルまで統合します。
thymic level
胸腺レベルまで
and the entire facial plane that will organize itself, for example, with mesodermal
そして、例えば中胚葉レベルで組織化される顔面全体。
levels
中胚葉レベルで
of the type of Meckel's cartilage, cart...
メッケル軟骨、リッヒャー軟骨のような、これらすべての領域。
Richer's cartilage, all these areas.
リッヒャー軟骨、これらすべての領域。
So we're going to study this whole journey of the digestive system,
したがって、消化器系のこの経路全体を少し研究します。
from its system here,
ここにあるそのシステムから、
so at the level of the mouth, at the level of the tongue,
つまり、口のレベル、舌のレベル、
at the level of the thyroid, a little at the level of the epiphysis,
甲状腺のレベル、少し松果体のレベル、
the lungs, the stomach, the esophagus, the liver, etc.
肺、胃、食道、肝臓など。
We're going to study all of that in detail here.
これらすべてをここで詳細に研究します。
What do I digest in my body?
私の体の中で何を消化していますか？
What do I give back?
何を排出していますか？
I take something I eat,
私は食べるものを取り、
I take something I'm going to pick up.
私は拾うものを取り、
this in the form of energy, meaning I will completely fragment it down to amino acids
それをエネルギーの形にします。つまり、アミノ酸になるまで完全に断片化し、
to be reused by your cellular system,
あなたの細胞システムによって再利用されるようにします。
protein, etc., molecular. I will make it
タンパク質など、分子レベルのものです。私はそれを
almost pure energy that the body needs to restructure itself
体が再構築するために必要な、ほとんど純粋なエネルギーに変えます。
and then I will
そして、私は
also eliminate the waste from that. So this elimination phase is very important.
そこから出る老廃物も排除します。この排泄の段階は非常に重要です。
three major sources of elimination phases.
排泄の段階には3つの大きな源があります。
We have a phase that occurs through feces,
便による排泄、
through urine, through respiration.
尿による排泄、呼吸による排泄です。
And so, it happens in the form
そして、それは
of upper gases.
上部のガスとして行われます。
The lungs
肺は
support the colon.
結腸を支えています。
If you want to support a lung,
肺を支えたいなら、
you have to work on its colon.
その結腸を治療しなければなりません。
Because the lungs,
なぜなら、肺は
it's endoderm.
内胚葉だからです。
It's a digestive tissue.
それは消化組織です。
And how
そして、
How can we know that I have a weak lung through this reflection?
この考察から、どうすれば肺が弱いとわかるのでしょうか？
A large amount of salt, in its entirety, you see.
大量の塩分、全体的に見て、わかりますか。
I remind you that osteopathy will tell you the story of anatomy
オステオパシーは、解剖学の歴史を語るものだとお話ししました。
in motion.
動きの中で。
There is a perpetual movement in the body, which never stops.
体には絶え間ない動きがあり、止まることはありません。
Always remember that we have this notion of accepting time,
常に、時間を受け入れるという概念を忘れてはなりません。
accepting the time of tissues, accepting the time of fluids.
組織の時間を受け入れ、体液の時間を受け入れることです。
with a level of constellation, spirit, mind, body, which
星座、精神、心、体のレベルが
are united.
統合されています。
We will see that your digestive tract also carries your level of emotion.
消化管が感情のレベルも担っていることがわかるでしょう。
And we will see that there are even molecular levels that we will find on
そして、脳のレベルでさえ、分子レベルで
the cerebral plane,
見られることがわかるでしょう。
which will react synchronously and show us that what happens in your
それらは同期して反応し、腸で起こっていることが
intestine
あなたの
may even influence your way of thinking.
考え方にさえ影響を与える可能性があることを示しています。
The endoderm, always in relation with the mesoderm, that is to say with the relational tissue
内胚葉は常に中胚葉、つまり内胚葉との関係組織と関連しています。
to the endoderm.
内胚葉に。
The concept, we can say visceral, is a concept based on the integrity
内臓という概念は、体の統合性に基づいた概念です。
of the body.
体の。
You must understand that.
これを理解しなければなりません。
You can very well, the visceral system can very well influence
内臓系は、皮質系に影響を与えるだけでなく、
a cortical system
皮質系に影響を与えるだけでなく、
or influence a parietal or musculoskeletal system.
頭頂系や筋骨格系にも影響を与える可能性があります。
And so we will see how this will impact in relation to its peritoneum, in relation
それが腹膜にどう影響するか、交感神経系にどう影響するか、
to the sympathetic system, in relation to the parasympathetic system and in relation to your nutritive system.
副交感神経系にどう影響するか、そして栄養システムにどう影響するかを見ていきます。
Because that's one of the most important things.
なぜなら、それが最も重要なことの一つだからです。
We attach a lot, a lot of importance to breathing.
私たちは呼吸に非常に、非常に重要性を置いています。
We attach a lot of importance to food.
私たちは食事に非常に重要性を置いています。
There are certain molecules like I think certain prostaglandins.
ある種の分子、例えばある種のプロスタグランジンなど、
or I don't know which ones, will really explode in their
あるいは他の何だったか忘れましたが、それらはその機能において同時に本当に爆発的に作用します。
functions at the same time.
同時に。
So what happens here will really have an influence on what happens
ですから、ここで起こることは、あそこで起こることに本当に影響を与えるでしょう。
there.
あそこで。
We knew it, but now we're discovering how.
私たちはそれを知っていましたが、今ではその仕組みを発見しています。
And the link between the two is probably the microbial flora.
そして、その二つの間のつながりは、おそらく微生物叢でしょう。
It's probably your bacteria.
おそらくあなたの細菌でしょう。
We have...
私たちは...
ten times more bacteria in the gut than the total number of
お腹の中には、T細胞の総数よりも10倍多くの細菌がいます。
T-cells.
T細胞。
We will study this intestinal flora both as a system
私たちはこの腸内フローラを、発酵システムと腐敗システムの両方として研究します。
of fermentation and a system of putrefaction.
発酵システムと腐敗システムの両方として。
I am in a balance in my allostatic system
私は恒常性状態を求めるアロスタシスシステムの中でバランスをとっています。
that seeks the homeostatic state.
恒常性状態を求める。
I am in a state where...
私はある状態にいます...
I am in a balance between my fermentation and my putrefaction.
私は発酵と腐敗のバランスの中にいます。
If I am in balance, I have a digestion, a digestive discernment
もし私がバランスが取れていれば、私は正しい消化、消化の識別を持っています。
that is just.
正しい消化の識別。
And in fact, it's always a question of territory.
そして実際、それは常に領域の問題です。
If I take your territory, if I invade you, I
もし私があなたの領域を奪い、あなたを侵略するなら、私はあなたのバランスを乱すでしょう。
will disturb your balance.
あなたのバランスを乱すでしょう。
Everyone has their space and it's very important to help that. Fermentation
誰もが自分の空間を持っており、それを助けることは非常に重要です。発酵は
is dependent
依存しています
also on another quality, the influence of the seasons. Four seasons but there are
また、もう一つの質、季節の影響にも。四季がありますが、
also four inter-seasons. Fasting
また、四つの間季節もあります。断食は
is always linked to the inter-season.
常に間季節と関連しています。
This is where the body regenerates. Equinox
そこでは体が再生します。春分は
here and I
ここにあり、そして私は
I'm coming in now, I'm between the 15th of February and the 21st of March, I'm in the
私は今、2月15日から3月21日の間にいます。私は上昇期にあり、すでに春の状態にいます。
ascension, I'm already in a state of spring.
上昇期にあり、すでに春の状態にいます。
Then I have the highest moment, and then
そして、最も高い瞬間があり、そして
I go down to arrive on the 27th of April, I enter the inter-season
私は下降し、4月27日に到着し、間季節の期間に入ります。
period.
間季節の期間に入ります。
So this is spring, this is summer, this is
ですから、これは春、これは夏、これは
autumn.
秋。
This is winter.
これは冬です。
Here, from April 27th to May 15th,
ここでは、4月27日から5月15日まで、
you are in the inter-season period.
あなたは季節の変わり目にいます。
It lasts 18 days.
それは18日間続きます。
It's the adaptation period from one season to another.
それはある季節から別の季節への適応期間です。
Spring is the color of the liver.
春は肝臓の色です。
The liver, then I have the liver and then I can add the hours,
肝臓、それから私は肝臓を持っていて、それから私は時間を追加することができます、
I can add my organs, I can add my seasons,
私は臓器を追加することができます、私は季節を追加することができます、
I can add my colors.
私は色を追加することができます。
And the best fasts are during the inter-season period.
そして最高の若者は季節の変わり目にいます。
But you don't fast just any old way either.
しかし、私たちはどんな断食でもするわけではありません。
It's something that is prepared, it's something that is cleansed.
それは準備されるものであり、それは浄化されるものです。
Because when you start fasting, you release toxins into the body.
なぜなら、断食を始めると、体内の毒素を放出するからです。
In general, most people lack water.
一般的に、ほとんどの人は水不足です。
Why? Because water will give you an interconnection in your body.
なぜですか？なぜなら、水はあなたの体内で相互接続を与えるからです。
We all, as human beings, have a quality of
私たちは皆、人間として、
clarity, interconnection, clairvoyance.
明晰さ、相互接続性、透視能力を持っています。
We have this capacity for clairvoyance.
私たちはこの透視能力を持っています。
What allows this, among other things, is your water quality, the
とりわけ、それを可能にするのは、あなたの水分量、つまり、
quality of water in your body.
あなたの体内の水の質です。
Hippocrates, when he traveled from village to village at the time,
ヒポクラテスが当時村から村へと旅をしていたとき、
the first thing he did was go to the source.
彼が最初にしたことは、水源に行くことでした。
He would taste the water, sodium, sulfurous, copper, whatever.
彼は水、ナトリウム、硫黄、銅、何でも味わいに行きました。
In the bourgeoisie, at the time, doctors always asked,
ブルジョアジーでは、当時、医者はいつも尋ねました、
how are you?
ご機嫌いかがですか？
To her.
彼女に。
And I will also teach you how to observe a face.
そして、顔を観察する方法も教えます。
To observe, to know how to read via the neural crest system,
神経堤系、消化器系を介して、
of the digestive system.
観察し、読み取る方法を学びます。
Because the face here, your whole skull, is ecto.
なぜなら、ここの顔、あなたの頭蓋骨全体は外胚葉だからです。
Neural Crest type derm.
神経堤型の真皮。
This means that there will be a link between your digestive system,
それは、あなたの消化器系との間に、
by a sympathetic, peripheral, deep pathway
交感神経経路、末梢神経、深部神経を介して、
to the periphery,
末梢でつながりができることを意味します。
but it means that through a precise observation of wrinkles, colors, shapes,
しかし、それはしわ、色、形、
of the type of tongue, of the type of uncle, etc., it will be a therapeutic tool.
舌のタイプ、叔父のタイプなどを正確に観察することで、治療ツールになることを意味します。
So that means what is your vitality?
つまり、あなたの活力は何ですか？
This means that the body expresses an electrical state.
それは、体が電気的な状態を表現していることを意味します。
It expresses a vitality in the form of an electromagnetic field.
それは電磁場の形で活力を表現します。
So finally, there are four important therapeutic levels.
つまり、最終的に重要な治療レベルは4つあります。
It's about learning to put people back in their gravity.
それは、人々を彼らの重力に戻すことを学ぶことです。
In gravity.
重力の中に。
That is, in reality.
つまり、現実の中に。
Are people on Earth or are they suspended like this?
人々は地球の上にいるのか、それともこのように宙に浮いているのか？
There are people who are not there.
そこにいない人もいます。
It's about coming back to Earth.
それは地球に戻ることです。
When I stand in front of someone, I feel the gravity of that person.
誰かと向き合うとき、私はその人の重力を感じます。
Then, you have to put people back in the electromagnetic field of
それから、人々を彼らの体の電磁場に戻す必要があります。
their body.
彼らの体。
The axis of your body is an electric field, with an electromagnetic field.
あなたの体の軸は電場であり、電磁場を持っています。
If this field is correct, you are in your body.
この場が正しければ、あなたは自分の体の中にいます。
Sometimes, an accident or I don't know, makes you leave your field.
時々、事故か何かで、あなたは自分の場を離れてしまいます。
In eight beaches, you are not.
8つのビーチでは、あなたはそうではありません。
in your electric field. And then, you have to put people back in the atomic field,
あなたの電場の中に。そして、人々を原子場、
in this energetic field. And then, very importantly, it
このエネルギー場に戻す必要があります。そして、非常に重要なのは、
is to put people back in the
人々を光の中、彼らの光の中に戻すことです。そして、そこにこの生命力があります。
light, in their light. And that's where this vitality is.
そこにこの生命力があります。
If you put
もしあなたが人々を彼らの光の中に戻すなら、あなたは人々を彼らの機能の中、
people back in their light, you put people in their function, what they
彼らが来た目的の中に置くことになります。
came for.
私は輝いているのか、そうでないのか？この質問を自問してください。
yourself this question. Am I
この質問を自問してください。私は自分の機能の中にいるのか？
in my function? There
私は自分の機能の中にいるのか？
are people, when they enter a room, they illuminate the room. I've already said that. There are people, when they leave the room, they illuminate
部屋に入ると部屋を明るくする人がいます。